<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<items>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benevolent_dictator_for_life</url><title>Benevolent dictator for life</title><text>For the political term, see Benevolent dictatorship.Benevolent dictator for life (BDFL) is a title given to a small number of open-source software development leaders, typically project founders who retain the final say in disputes or arguments within the community. The phrase originated in 1995 with reference to Guido van Rossum, creator of the Python programming language.[1][2] Shortly after Van Rossum joined the Corporation for National Research Initiatives, the term appeared in a follow-up mail by Ken Manheimer to a meeting trying to create a semi-formal group that would oversee Python development and workshops; this initial use included an additional joke of naming Van Rossum the "First Interim BDFL".[1] Van Rossum announced on July 12, 2018, that he would be stepping down as BDFL of Python.[3]BDFL should not be confused with the more common term for open-source leaders, "benevolent dictator", which was popularized by Eric S. Raymond's essay "Homesteading the Noosphere" (1999).[4] Among other topics related to hacker culture, Raymond elaborates on how the nature of open source forces the "dictatorship" to keep itself benevolent, since a strong disagreement can lead to the forking of the project under the rule of new leaders.
Referrant candidates[edit]

Name
Project
</text><lastUpdated>2020-05-11 21:48:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homesteading_the_Noosphere</url><title>Homesteading the Noosphere</title><text>"Homesteading the Noosphere" (abbreviated HtN) is an essay written by Eric S. Raymond about the social workings of open-sourcesoftware development. It follows his previous piece "The Cathedral and the Bazaar" (1997).
The essay examines issues of project ownership and transfer, as well as investigating possible anthropological roots of the gift culture in open source as contrasted with the exchange culture of closed source software. Raymond also investigates the nature of the spread of open source into the untamed frontier of ideas he terms the noosphere, postulating that projects that range too far ahead of their time fail because they are too far out in the wilderness, and that successful projects tend to relate to existing projects.
Raymond delves into the contrast between the stated aims of open source and observed behaviors, and also explores the underlying motivations of people involved in the open source movement. He notes that a key motivation for open source practitioners is having a great reputation within the "tribe".
Contents1Citations2In popular culture3See also4References</text><lastUpdated>2020-04-17 19:59:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spacemacs</url><title>Spacemacs</title><text>Free softwareSpacemacsSpacemacs with recent files and editing windows openOriginal author(s)Sylvain Benner[1]Developer(s)Sylvain Benner and many others[2]Initial release30 October 2014; 5 years ago (2014-10-30)Stable release0.200.13[3]
   / 25 January 2018; 2 years ago (2018-01-25)Written inEmacs LispOperating systemUnix, Linux, Windows NT, macOSAvailable inEnglish (by default)TypeText editorLicenseGPLv3[4]Websitespacemacs.orgSpacemacs is a configuration framework for </text><lastUpdated>2019-06-13 12:29:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ken_Manheimer</url><title>Ken Manheimer</title><text>Ken Manheimer has been a prominent software developer of Zope and GNU Mailman who worked for NIST, CNRI, Digital Creations and Zope Corporation, and SpiderOak. He's been listed by Guido van Rossum together with Barry Warsaw as the probable inventor of the term Benevolent Dictator For Life (during his CNRI tenure).[1]Famous quotes[edit]"computers usefulness is ridiculously improbable.  you can quote me."References[edit]^"Origin of BDFL". Archived from the original on 2010-12-20..mw-parser-output cite.citation{font-style:inherit}.mw-parser-output .citation q{quotes:"\"""\"""'""'"}.mw-parser-output .id-lock-free a,.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-free a{background-image:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/65/Lock-green.svg/9px-Lock-green.svg.png");background-image:linear-gradient(transparent,transparent),url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/6/65/Lock-green.svg");background-repeat:no-repeat;background-size:9px;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .id-lock-limited a,.mw-parser-output .id-lock-registration a,.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-limited a,.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-registration a{background-image:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d6/Lock-gray-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-gray-alt-2.svg.png");background-image:linear-gradient(transparent,transparent),url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/d/d6/Lock-gray-alt-2.svg");background-repeat:no-repeat;background-size:9px;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .id-lock-subscription a,.mw-parser-output .citation .cs1-lock-subscription a{background-image:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/aa/Lock-red-alt-2.svg/9px-Lock-red-alt-2.svg.png");background-image:linear-gradient(transparent,transparent),url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/a/aa/Lock-red-alt-2.svg");background-repeat:no-repeat;background-size:9px;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration{color:#555}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription span,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration span{border-bottom:1px dotted;cursor:help}.mw-parser-output .cs1-ws-icon a{background-image:url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/4c/Wikisource-logo.svg/12px-Wikisource-logo.svg.png");background-image:linear-gradient(transparent,transparent),url("//upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/4/4c/Wikisource-logo.svg");background-repeat:no-repeat;background-size:12px;background-position:right .1em center}.mw-parser-output code.cs1-code{color:inherit;background:inherit;border:inherit;padding:inherit}.mw-parser-output .cs1-hidden-error{display:none;font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-visible-error{font-size:100%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-maint{display:none;color:#33aa33;margin-left:0.3em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-subscription,.mw-parser-output .cs1-registration,.mw-parser-output .cs1-format{font-size:95%}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-left,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-left{padding-left:0.2em}.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-right,.mw-parser-output .cs1-kern-wl-right{padding-right:0.2em}.mw-parser-output .citation .mw-selflink{font-weight:inherit}"Feasting on life with veteran programmer Ken Manheimer".</text><lastUpdated>2019-12-19 16:41:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corporation_for_National_Research_Initiatives</url><title>Corporation for National Research Initiatives</title><text>The Corporation for National Research Initiatives (CNRI), based in Reston, Virginia, is a non-profit organization founded in 1986 by Robert E. Kahn as an "activities center around strategic development of network-based information technologies", including the National Information Infrastructure (NII) in the United States.[1]CNRI develops the Handle System for managing and locating digital information.[2]  CNRI obtained DARPA funding for the development of JPython (Jython), a Python implementation in and for Java, initially created by Jim Hugunin.[3]Contents1History2Handle System3D-Lib4Software</text><lastUpdated>2019-09-17 04:08:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fork_(software_development)</url><title>Fork (software development)</title><text>  A timeline chart of how Linux distributions have forked.In software engineering, a project fork happens when developers take a copy of source code from one software package and start independent development on it, creating a distinct and separate piece of software. The term often implies not merely a development branch, but also a split in the developer community, a form of schism.[1]Free and open-source software is that which, by definition, may be forked from the original development team without prior permission, without violating copyright law. However, licensed forks of proprietary software (e.g.Unix) also happen.
Contents1Etymology2Forking of free and open-source software3Forking proprietary software4See also5</text><lastUpdated>2020-02-29 06:52:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eric_S._Raymond</url><title>Eric S. Raymond</title><text>American computer programmer, author, and advocate for the open source movement"Eric Raymond" redirects here. For other uses, see Eric Raymond (disambiguation).This article may rely excessively on sources too closely associated with the subject, potentially preventing the article from being verifiable and neutral. Please help improve it by replacing them with more appropriate citations to reliable, independent, third-party sources.  (July 2015) (Learn how and when to remove this template message)Eric S. RaymondRaymond at Linucon 2004Born (1957-12-04) December 4, 1957 (age 62)Boston, MassachusettsNationalityAmericanAlma materUniversity of Pennsylvania (dropped out)[1]OccupationSoftware developer</text><lastUpdated>2020-03-11 09:10:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hacker_culture</url><title>Hacker culture</title><text>Subculture of individualsNot to be confused with Security hacker.This article has multiple issues. Please help improve it or discuss these issues on the talk page. (Learn how and when to remove these template messages)
      This article's tone or style may not reflect the encyclopedic tone used on Wikipedia. See Wikipedia's guide to writing better articles for suggestions.  (June 2011) (Learn how and when to remove this template message)This article needs additional citations for verification. Please help improve this article by adding citations to reliable sources. Unsourced material may be challenged and removed.Find sources: "Hacker culture" – news </text><lastUpdated>2020-03-31 12:21:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open-source_software_development</url><title>Open-source software development</title><text>Open-source software development is the process by which open-source software, or similar software whose source code is publicly available, is developed by an open-source software project. These are software products available with its source code under an open-source license to study, change, and improve its design. Examples of some popular open-source software products are Mozilla Firefox, Google Chromium, Android, LibreOffice and the VLC media player. Open-source software development has been a large part of the creation of the World Wide Web as we know it, with Tim Berners-Lee contributing his HTML code development as the original platform upon which the internet is now built.[1]Contents1History2Model2.1Starting an open-source project3Types of open-source projects4Methods</text><lastUpdated>2020-04-25 04:52:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guido_van_Rossum</url><title>Guido van Rossum</title><text>Dutch programmer and creator of Python"GvR" redirects here. For other uses, see gvr (disambiguation).In this Dutch name, the family name is van Rossum, not Rossum.Guido van RossumGuido van Rossum at the Dropbox headquarters in 2014Born (1956-01-31) 31 January 1956 (age 64)[1]Haarlem, Netherlands[2][3]NationalityDutchAlma materUniversity of AmsterdamOccupationComputer programmer, authorKnown forCreating the Python programming languageSpouse(s)Kim Knapp (m. 2000)Children1[4]</text><lastUpdated>2020-05-09 18:23:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vim_(text_editor)</url><title>Vim (text editor)</title><text>Improved version of the Vi keyboard-oriented text editorVimVim running in a terminal emulatorOriginal author(s)Bram MoolenaarInitial release2 November 1991(28 years ago) (1991-11-02)Stable release8.2.0000[1] (13 December 2019; 4 months ago (2019-12-13)) [±]Repositorygithub.com/vim/vimWritten inC, Vim scriptOperating systemUnix, Linux, Windows NT, MS-DOS, macOS, iOS, Android, </text><lastUpdated>2020-04-28 10:34:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Python_programming_language</url><title>Python (programming language)</title><text>General-purpose, high-level programming languagePythonParadigmMulti-paradigm: functional, imperative, object-oriented, structured, reflectiveDesigned byGuido van RossumDeveloperPython Software FoundationFirst appeared1990; 30 years ago (1990)[1]Stable release3.8.2
   / 24 February 2020; 2 months ago (2020-02-24)[2]Preview release3.9.0a6
   / 28 April 2020; 15 days ago (2020-04-28)[3]Typing disciplineDuck, dynamic, gradual (since 3.5)</text><lastUpdated>2020-05-13 11:59:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matt_Mullenweg</url><title>Matt Mullenweg</title><text>This article contains content that is written like an advertisement. Please help improve it by removing promotional content and inappropriate external links, and by adding encyclopedic content written from a neutral point of view.  (June 2019) (Learn how and when to remove this template message)American social media entrepreneur and web developer best known for developing WordPressMatt MullenwegMullenweg at WordCamp Kansai in 2014BornMatthew Charles Mullenweg (1984-01-11) January 11, 1984 (age 36)Houston, Texas, USNationalityAmericanCitizenshipUnited StatesAlma materUniversity of HoustonOccupationFounder &amp; CEO,[1] CBBQTT[2]AutomatticPrincipal</text><lastUpdated>2020-05-07 19:59:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linux.com</url><title>Linux.com</title><text>This article has multiple issues. Please help improve it or discuss these issues on the talk page. (Learn how and when to remove these template messages)
      This article's factual accuracy may be compromised due to out-of-date information. Please update this article to reflect recent events or newly available information.  (November 2010)This article needs additional citations for verification. Please help improve this article by adding citations to reliable sources. Unsourced material may be challenged and removed.Find sources: "Linux.com" – news ·newspapers ·books ·scholar ·</text><lastUpdated>2020-02-28 11:59:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benevolent_dictatorship</url><title>Benevolent dictatorship</title><text>  Mustafa Kemal Atatürk in 1923A benevolent dictatorship refers to a government in which an authoritarian leader exercises absolute political power over the state but is perceived to do so with regard for benefit of the population as a whole, standing in contrast to the decidedly malevolent stereotype of a dictator who focuses on their and their supporters' self-interests. A benevolent dictator may allow for some economic liberalization or democratic decision-making to exist, such as through public referenda or electedrepresentatives with limited power, and often makes preparations for a transition to genuine democracy during or after their term. It might be seen as a republican form of enlightened despotism.
The label has been applied to leaders such as Sultan Qaboos bin Said of Oman (1970–2020),[1]Mustafa Kemal Atatürk of Turkey (1923–38),[2]Josip Broz Tito of Yugoslavia (1953–80),[3]Lee Kuan Yew of </text><lastUpdated>2020-05-10 09:02:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordPress</url><title>WordPress</title><text>Free and open-source content management systemThis article is about the web content management system (WordPress.org). For the blog host, see WordPress.com.

WordPressDeveloper(s)WordPress FoundationInitial releaseMay 27, 2003; 16 years ago (2003-05-27)[1]Stable release5.4.1[2]
   / 2020-04-29[±]Repositorycore.trac.wordpress.org/browserWritten inPHPOperating systemUnix-like, Windows, LinuxTypeBlog software, content management system, content management frameworkLicenseGPLv2+[3]Website</text><lastUpdated>2020-05-13 09:43:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emacs</url><title>Emacs</title><text>Family of text editorsNot to be confused with eMac.This article is about the class of text editors. For the most popular current example, see GNU Emacs.EmacsEditing multiple Dired buffers in GNU EmacsOriginal author(s)Carl Mikkelsen,David A. Moon,Guy L. Steele Jr.Developer(s)Various open-source and commercial developersInitial release1976; 44 years ago (1976)[1][2]Stable release26.3 (August 28, 2019; 8 months ago (2019-08-28)) [±]Written inLisp, COperating systemCross-platform</text><lastUpdated>2020-05-13 08:51:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Main_Page</url><title>Main Page</title><text>body.skin-minerva .mw-parser-output table,body.skin-minerva .mw-parser-output tr,body.skin-minerva .mw-parser-output td,body.skin-minerva .mw-parser-output tbody{display:block!important;width:100%!important;box-sizing:border-box}body.skin-minerva .mw-parser-output #mp-topbanner{min-width:0!important;white-space:initial!important}body.skin-minerva .mw-parser-output #mp-topbanner&gt;ul{display:none}body.skin-minerva .mw-parser-output #mp-topbanner&gt;div{width:auto!important}body.skin-minerva .mw-parser-output #mp-tfp tr td:first-child a{text-align:center;display:block}body.skin-minerva .mw-parser-output #sister-projects-list&gt;div{width:49%}Welcome to Wikipedia,the freeencyclopedia that anyone can edit.6,077,169 articles in EnglishArtsBiographyGeographyHistoryMathematicsScienceSocietyTechnologyAll portalsFrom today's featured articleConnor Trinneer</text><lastUpdated>2020-05-12 18:36:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/EWeek</url><title>None</title><text>eWEEKEditor-in-ChiefChris Preimesberger (since 2018)CategoriesComputer magazine, Business magazineFrequencyonline onlyCirculation20M pageviews/yearYear founded1983Final issue2012CompanyQuinStreetCountryUnited StatesLanguageEnglishWebsiteeweek.comISSN1530-6283eWeek (Enterprise Newsweekly, stylized as eWEEK), formerly PCWeek,[1] is a technology and business magazine, owned by Foster City, California marketing company QuinStreet.  
The print edition ceased in 2012, "and eWeek became an all-digital publication"),[2] at which time Quinstreet acquired the magazine from Internet company Ziff Davis, along with Baseline.com, ChannelInsider.com,  CIOInsight.com, and WebBuyersGuide.com.[3]eWeek</text><lastUpdated>2020-03-24 16:03:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calculation_in_kind</url><title>Calculation in kind</title><text>Part of a series onSocialismDevelopmentAge of the EnlightenmentFrench RevolutionHistory of socialismRevolutions of 1848Socialist calculation debateSocialist economicsIdeasCalculation in kindCollective ownershipCooperativeCommon ownershipCommune (model of government)Economic democracyEconomic planningEqual opportunityFree associationFreed marketIndustrial democracyInput–output modelInternationalismLabor-time calculation</text><lastUpdated>2020-03-30 01:43:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wolfram_Research</url><title>Wolfram Research</title><text>Wolfram Research, Inc.TypePrivateIndustryComputer software, Publishing, Research and DevelopmentFounded1987; 33 years ago (1987)FounderStephen Wolfram, Theodore GrayHeadquartersChampaign, Illinois (worldwide headquarters)Oxfordshire, UKTokyo, Japan with additional locations in Bangalore, India, Lima, Peru, Linköping, Sweden, Paris, France, and Somerville, Massachusetts.Key peopleStephen Wolfram (President &amp; CEO); Conrad Wolfram (Director of Strategic Development &amp; Wolfram Research Europe Limited CEO)ProductsWolfram Mathematica, Wolfram Workbench, gridMathematica, webMathematica, Wolfram Alpha, SystemModeler, Wolfram Programming Lab, Wolfram One, Wolfram Engine for Developers, Function Repository, Neural Network Repository, Data Repository</text><lastUpdated>2020-05-09 22:26:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ISBN_(identifier)</url><title>International Standard Book Number</title><text>Not to be confused with ICCU SBN.Unique numeric book identifierInternational Standard Book NumberA 13-digit ISBN, 978-3-16-148410-0, as represented by an EAN-13 bar codeAcronymISBNOrganisationInternational ISBN AgencyIntroduced1970; 50 years ago (1970)No. of digits13 (formerly 10)Check digitWeighted sumExample978-3-16-148410-0Websiteisbn-international.orgThe International Standard Book Number (ISBN) is a numeric commercial bookidentifier which is intended to be unique.[a][b] Publishers purchase ISBNs from an affiliate of the International ISBN Agency.[1]An ISBN is assigned to each separate edition and variation (except reprintings) of a publication. For example, an e-book, a paperback</text><lastUpdated>2020-05-11 19:03:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CNET</url><title>CNET</title><text>"CNET Networks" redirects here. For the successor online media company, see CBS Interactive."News.com" redirects here. For the Australian news website, see news.com.au.For Centre National d'Études des Télécommunications (CNET), the research and development centre of France Télécom, see France Télécom and Centre national d'études des télécommunications.American media website about technology and consumer electronicsCNETScreenshotType of siteTechnology NewsOwnerCBS Interactive(ViacomCBS)Created byHalsey Minor Shelby BonnieEditorLindsey Turrentine  Connie GuglielmoIndustryJournalismURLcnet.comAlexa rank 163 (As of April 24, 2020[update])[1]CommercialYesRegistrationOptional</text><lastUpdated>2020-04-30 18:05:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Massively_multiplayer_online_role-playing_game</url><title>Massively multiplayer online role-playing game</title><text>Part of a series onRole-playing video gamesSubgenresAction RPGMUDMMORPGRoguelikeTactical RPG
TopicsSocial interaction in MMORPGsCharacter creationDialog treeGNS TheoryHistory of Eastern RPGsHistory of MMORPGsHistory of Western RPGsNon-player characterPlayer characterQuestRPG termsStatisticsThreefold Model
ListsList of RPGsList of MUDsList of roguelikes</text><lastUpdated>2020-04-23 18:30:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linux_Foundation</url><title>Linux Foundation</title><text>non-profit technology consortium to develop the Linux operating systemThe Linux FoundationPredecessorOpen Source Development LabsFree Standards GroupFormation2000; 20 years ago (2000)Type501(c)(6) organizationPurposeBuild sustainable ecosystems around open source projects to accelerate technology development and commercial adoption.LocationSan Francisco, CaliforniaMembership  1,000+ corporate members[1]Key peopleKey peopleLinus TorvaldsJim ZemlinMike WosterMike DolanKaren CopenhaverAbby KearnsArpit JoshipuraBrian BehlendorfAndy UpdegroveAngela BrownChris AniszczykHeather KirkseyKate StewartDan CauchyNoriaki FukuyasuClyde SeepersadDan KohnCalista RedmondRobin GinnShubhra KarEmployees  150Website</text><lastUpdated>2020-05-03 12:53:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dissociated_press</url><title>Dissociated press</title><text>Dissociated press is a parody generator (a computer program that generates nonsensical text). The generated text is based on another text using the Markov chain technique. The name is a play on "Associated Press" and the psychiatric term dissociative identity disorder (which may result in somewhat similar word salad during quick switches between personalities).
An implementation of the algorithm is available in Emacs. Another implementation is available as a Perl module in CPAN, Games::Dissociate.[1]Contents1The algorithm2Examples3History4See also5References</text><lastUpdated>2019-12-13 20:47:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conkeror</url><title>Conkeror</title><text>Not to be confused with Konqueror.ConkerorConkeror web browser running on Ubuntu Linux 10.04Developer(s)Shawn Betts, John J. Foerch, Jeremy Maitin-ShepardStable release1.0.4[1]
   / November 29, 2017; 2 years ago (2017-11-29)Written inJavaScriptOperating systemCross-platformPlatformXULRunnerTypeWeb browserLicenseGNU GPL, GNU LGPL and MPLWebsiteconkeror.orgConkeror is a Mozilla-based web browser designed to be navigated primarily by a computer keyboard. Its design is mainly patterned after the text editor GNU Emacs, with some influence from other programs, including vi.[2]It was originally written by </text><lastUpdated>2020-02-17 07:49:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anime</url><title>Anime</title><text>Not to be confused with Amine.Japanese animation



Part of a series onAnime and mangaAnimeHistoryIndustryOriginal net animationOriginal video animationFansubFandubCompaniesLongest seriesLongest franchiseListsMangaHistoryInternational marketMangakaDōjinshiScanlationAlternative</text><lastUpdated>2020-05-04 14:00:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guy_L._Steele_Jr.</url><title>Guy L. Steele Jr.</title><text>American computer scientist (born 1954)This article has multiple issues. Please help improve it or discuss these issues on the talk page. (Learn how and when to remove these template messages)
      This article includes a list of references, but its sources remain unclear because it has insufficient inline citations. Please help to improve this article by introducing more precise citations.  (September 2016) (Learn how and when to remove this template message)This biography of a living personneeds additional citations for verification. Please help by adding reliable sources. Contentious material about living persons that is unsourced or poorly sourced must be removed immediately, especially if potentially libelous or harmful.Find sources: "Guy L. Steele Jr."</text><lastUpdated>2020-02-13 07:30:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Copyright</url><title>Copyright</title><text>Legal concept regulating rights of a creator to their workThis article is about the legal right. For the symbol, see Copyright symbol. For the band, see Copyright (band). For the Wikipedia policy, see Wikipedia:Copyrights.Not to be confused with Copywriting.Intellectual propertyAuthors' rightsCopyrightDatabase rightFarmers' rightsGeographical indicationIndigenous intellectual propertyIndustrial design rightIntegrated circuit layout design protectionIntellectual rightsMoral rightsPatentPeasants' rightsPlant breeders' rightsPlant genetic resourcesRelated rightsSupplementary protection certificateTrade dress</text><lastUpdated>2020-05-04 14:32:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Stallman</url><title>Richard Stallman</title><text>American free software activist

Richard StallmanStallman in 2019BornRichard Matthew Stallman (1953-03-16) March 16, 1953 (age 67)New York City, New York, USOther namesrms, RMSAlma materHarvard UniversityMassachusetts Institute of TechnologyOccupationActivistprogrammerKnown forFree software movementGNUEmacsGCCGPLcopyleftFSFAwardsMacArthur FellowshipACM Grace Murray Hopper AwardEFF Pioneer AwardACM Software System AwardWebsitestallman.orgRichard Matthew Stallman (/ˈs</text><lastUpdated>2020-05-12 14:08:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NetHack</url><title>None</title><text>Classical roguelike ASCII graphics computer game released in 1987NetHackA released djinni grants the player a wishDeveloper(s)The NetHack DevTeamInitial releaseJuly 1987 (1.3d)[1]Stable release3.6.6
   / 8 March 2020; 2 months ago (2020-03-08)Repositorygithub.com/NetHack/NetHackTypeRoguelikeLicenseNetHack General Public License (derivative of BISON general public license, a precursor to the GPL)Websitewww.nethack.org/ NetHack is a single-player roguelikevideo game originally released in 1987 with ASCII graphics. It is a descendant of an earlier game called Hack</text><lastUpdated>2020-04-27 15:32:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roguelike</url><title>Roguelike</title><text>

  A procedurally-generated dungeon in the 1980 video game Rogue, the game after which the roguelike genre is namedPart of a series onRole-playing video gamesSubgenresAction RPGMUDMMORPGRoguelikeTactical RPG
TopicsSocial interaction in MMORPGsCharacter creationDialog treeGNS TheoryHistory of Eastern RPGsHistory of MMORPGsHistory of Western RPGsNon-player characterPlayer characterQuestRPG termsStatisticsThreefold Model</text><lastUpdated>2020-04-14 15:59:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniel_Weinreb</url><title>Daniel Weinreb</title><text>Daniel L. WeinrebBorn(1959-01-06)January 6, 1959Brooklyn, New York, United StatesDiedSeptember 7, 2012(2012-09-07) (aged 53)Massachusetts, United StatesCitizenshipUnited StatesEducationB.S., Massachusetts Institute of Technology (1979)Known forEINE, Symbolics, Common Lisp, ObjectStoreSpouse(s)Cheryl Moreau (m. 1986)ChildrenAdam WeinrebScientific careerFieldsComputer science, programmingInstitutionsLLNLSymbolicsObject Design, IncorporatedBEA SystemsITA SoftwareThesisA Real-Time Display-oriented Editor for the LISP Machine</text><lastUpdated>2020-04-06 10:36:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russ_Nelson</url><title>Russ Nelson</title><text>For other people with the same name, see Russell Nelson (disambiguation)."Crynwr" redirects here. For the Quakers, see Crynwyr.Russ NelsonRuss NelsonBorn (1958-03-21) March 21, 1958 (age 62)[1]OccupationSoftware developerKnown forBoard member and former president of Open Source Initiative[2]TermFebruary 2005[3]PredecessorEric S. Raymond[4]SuccessorMichael Tiemann[3]Political partyLibertarian Party[5]Websitehttp://russnelson.com/Russell "Russ" Nelson (born March 21, 1958) is an American computer programmer. He was a founding board member of the Open Source Initiative and briefly served as its president in 2005.[6]</text><lastUpdated>2020-04-15 14:34:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_Software_Foundation</url><title>Free Software Foundation</title><text>Non-profit organization for support for the free software movementFree Software FoundationAbbreviationFSFMottoFree Software, Free SocietyFormationOctober 4, 1985; 34 years ago (1985-10-04)[1]Type501(c)(3)non-profit organizationLegal status501(c)(3)PurposeEducationalHeadquartersBoston, Massachusetts, USRegion served WorldwideMembership  IndividualsBudget  $1,373,645 in FY 2017[2]Staff  13[3]Websitewww.fsf.orgThe Free Software Foundation (FSF) is a 501(c)(3)</text><lastUpdated>2020-05-08 02:07:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/University_of_Pennsylvania</url><title>University of Pennsylvania</title><text>Not to be confused with Pennsylvania State University.Private Ivy League research university in Philadelphia, PennsylvaniaUniversity of PennsylvaniaLatin: Universitas PennsylvaniensisMottoLeges sine moribus vanae (Latin)Motto in EnglishLaws without morals are uselessTypePrivateresearch universityEstablishedNovember 14, 1740 (1740-11-14)[note 1]FounderBenjamin FranklinEndowment$14.65 billion (2019)[4]Budget$3.5 billion (2020)[5]PresidentAmy GutmannProvostWendell PritchettBoard ChairmanDavid L. Cohen[6]Academic staff4,793 (2018)[7]Students22,432 (Fall 2019)[8]Undergraduates</text><lastUpdated>2020-05-12 00:51:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schism</url><title>Schism</title><text>For other uses, see Schism (disambiguation).Not to be confused with Shi'ism.A schism (pronounced /ˈsɪzəm/SIZ-əm, /ˈskɪzəm/SKIZ-əm or, less commonly, /ˈʃɪzəm/SHIZ-əm[1])  is a division between people, usually belonging to an organization, movement, or religious denomination</text><lastUpdated>2020-03-28 21:47:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_software_movement</url><title>Free software movement</title><text>Social and political movementNot to be confused with Open-source software movement, a related movement.  Richard Stallman circa 2002, founder of the GNU Project and the free software movement.The free software movement is a social movement with the goal of obtaining and guaranteeing certain freedoms for software users, namely the freedom to run the software, to study and change the software, and to redistribute copies with or without changes.[1][2]  Although drawing on traditions and philosophies among members of the 1970s hacker culture and academia, Richard Stallman formally founded the movement in 1983 by launching the GNU Project.[3] Stallman later established the Free Software Foundation in 1985 to support the movement.
Contents1Philosophy2Actions2.1Writing and spreading free software2.2</text><lastUpdated>2020-04-19 10:54:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Libertarian_Party_(United_States)</url><title>Libertarian Party (United States)</title><text>National political party in United StatesLibertarian PartyChairpersonNicholas Sarwark (NH)SecretaryCaryn Ann Harlos (CO)FoundedDecember 11, 1971; 48 years ago (1971-12-11)Headquarters1444 Duke St.Alexandria, Virginia 22314Membership (March 2020) 609,234[a][1]IdeologyMajority:Libertarianism[2]Classical liberalism[3]Cultural liberalism[3]Economic liberalism[3]Fiscal conservatism[3]Laissez-faire[3]Non-interventionism[4]Factions:Anarcho-capitalism[5]Libertarian conservatismLibertarian socialism</text><lastUpdated>2020-05-13 03:31:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_bug</url><title>Software bug</title><text>To report a MediaWiki error on Wikipedia, see Wikipedia:Bug reports.This article needs additional citations for verification. Please help improve this article by adding citations to reliable sources. Unsourced material may be challenged and removed.Find sources: "Software bug" – news ·newspapers ·books ·scholar ·JSTOR  (September 2017) (Learn how and when to remove this template message)Software development
Core activitiesProcesses</text><lastUpdated>2020-05-02 22:14:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IronPython</url><title>IronPython</title><text>This article relies too much on references to primary sources. Please improve this  by adding secondary or tertiary sources.  (January 2013) (Learn how and when to remove this template message)IronPythonOriginal author(s)Jim Hugunin, MicrosoftDeveloper(s)Dino Viehland, .NET FoundationInitial releaseSeptember 5, 2006; 13 years ago (2006-09-05)[1]Stable release2.7.10
   / April 27, 2020; 14 days ago (2020-04-27)[2]Repositorygithub.com/IronLanguages/ironpython2Written inC#Platform</text><lastUpdated>2020-05-11 17:58:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CircuitPython</url><title>CircuitPython</title><text>CircuitPythonOriginal author(s)Adafruit IndustriesInitial releaseJuly 19, 2017; 2 years ago (2017-07-19)[1]Stable release5.1.0
   / April 7, 2020; 36 days ago (2020-04-07)[2]Repositoryhttps://github.com/adafruit/circuitpythonWritten inC[3]Platformmicrocontroller boards using the Atmel SAMD21, Atmel SAMD51, Nordic nRF52840, and ESP8266 microcontrollers, from Adafruit, SparkFun, Arduino, Particle, and othersTypePython implementationLicenseMIT license[4]Websitecircuitpython.orgCircuitPython[5] is an  open source derivative of the MicroPython programming language targeted towards the student and beginner. Development of CircuitPython is supported by Adafruit Industries. It is a software implementation of the Python 3 programming language, written in C.</text><lastUpdated>2020-04-24 23:33:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ada_(programming_language)</url><title>Ada (programming language)</title><text>High-level programming language first released in 1980AdaParadigmMulti-paradigmFamilyPascalDesigned byMIL-STD-1815, Ada 83: Jean IchbiahAda 95: Tucker TaftAda 2005: Tucker TaftAda 2012: Tucker TaftFirst appearedFebruary 1980; 40 years ago (1980-02)Stable releaseAda 2012 TC1[1][2]
   / February 1, 2016; 4 years ago (2016-02-01)Preview releaseAda 2012 TC1[3]
   / April 2015; 5 years ago (2015-04)Typing disciplinestatic, strong, safe, nominative</text><lastUpdated>2020-05-03 06:32:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Julia_(programming_language)</url><title>Julia (programming language)</title><text>High-performance dynamic programming languageJuliaParadigmMulti-paradigm: multiple dispatch (core), procedural, functional, meta, multistaged[1]Designed byJeff Bezanson, Alan Edelman, Stefan Karpinski, Viral B. ShahDeveloperJeff Bezanson, Stefan Karpinski, Viral B. Shah, and other contributors[2][3]First appeared2012; 8 years ago (2012)[4]Stable release1.4.1[5]
   / 14 April 2020; 26 days ago (2020-04-14)Preview release1.6.0-DEV with daily updates (and 1.0.6</text><lastUpdated>2020-05-10 15:15:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MicroPython</url><title>MicroPython</title><text>MicroPythonOriginal author(s)Damien P. GeorgeInitial release3 May 2014; 5 years ago (2014-05-03)Stable release1.12
   / 20 December 2019; 4 months ago (2019-12-20)Repositorygithub.com/micropython/micropythonWritten inCPlatformARM Cortex-M, STM32, ESP8266, ESP32, 16bit PIC, Unix, Microsoft Windows, Zephyr, JavaScriptTypePython implementationLicenseMIT license[1]Website</text><lastUpdated>2020-04-22 06:21:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Genie_(programming_language)</url><title>Genie (programming language)</title><text>Not to be confused with ALGOL 68 Genie, or Geany.GenieParadigmmulti-paradigm: imperative, structured, object-orientedDesigned byJamie McCrackenFirst appeared2008; 12 years ago (2008)Stable release0.38.8
   /    February 15, 2018; 2 years ago (2018-02-15)Typing disciplinestatic, strongOSCross-platform (every platform supported by GLib)LicenseLGPLv2.1+Filename extensions.gsWebsitewiki.gnome.org/Projects/Genie</text><lastUpdated>2020-04-29 07:12:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/D_(programming_language)</url><title>D (programming language)</title><text>For other programming languages named D, see D (disambiguation) § Computing. For other uses, see D (disambiguation).Multi-paradigm system programming languageD programming languageParadigmMulti-paradigm: functional, imperative, object-orientedDesigned byWalter Bright, Andrei Alexandrescu (since 2007)DeveloperD Language FoundationFirst appearedDecember 8, 2001; 18 years ago (2001-12-08)[1]Stable release2.092.0[2]
   /    May 10, 2020; 3 days ago (2020-05-10)[2]Typing disciplineInferred, static, strongOS</text><lastUpdated>2020-05-13 05:20:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reference_implementation</url><title>Reference implementation</title><text>Look up reference implementation in Wiktionary, the free dictionary.In the software development process,  a reference implementation (or, less frequently, sample implementation or model implementation) is the standard from which all other implementations and corresponding customizations are derived. A reference implementation often accompanies a technical standard, and demonstrates what should be considered the "correct" behavior of any other implementation of it.
Characteristics and examples[edit]Reference implementations of algorithms, for instance cryptographic algorithms, are often the result or the input of standardization processes. In this function they are often dedicated to the public domain with their source code as public domain software. Examples are the first CERN's httpd,[1]Serpent cipher, base64 variants,[2] and SHA-3.[3] The </text><lastUpdated>2020-02-16 15:27:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ALGOL_68</url><title>ALGOL 68</title><text>ALGOL 68Revised Report on the Algorithmic Language – Algol 68 Edited by: A. van Wijngaarden et al, September 1973[1]ParadigmsMulti-paradigm: concurrent, imperativeFamilyALGOLDesigned byA. van Wijngaarden, B. J. Mailloux, J. E. L. Peck and C. H. A. Koster, et al.First appearedFinal Report: 1968; 52 years ago (1968)r0Stable releaseAlgol 68/RR
   / Revised Report: 1973; 47 years ago (1973)r1Typing disciplinestatic, strong, safe, structuralScopeLexicalMajor implementationsALGOL 68C</text><lastUpdated>2020-04-26 07:41:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Go_(programming_language)</url><title>Go (programming language)</title><text>Programming languageFor the language released in 2003 by McCabe and Clark, see Go! (programming language)."Google Go" redirects here. For the computer program by Google to play the board game Go, see AlphaGo.GoThe Go Programming LanguageParadigmMulti-paradigm: concurrent, functional,[1]imperative, object-oriented[2][3]Designed byRobert GriesemerRob PikeKen ThompsonDeveloperThe Go Authors[4]First appearedNovember 10, 2009; 10 years ago (2009-11-10)Stable release1.14.2
   /    April 8, 2020; 35 days ago (2020-04-08)[5]Typing disciplineInferred, </text><lastUpdated>2020-05-13 13:24:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Open_Definition</url><title>The Open Definition</title><text>  The Open content logoThe Open Definition is a document published by the Open Knowledge Foundation (OKF) (previously Open Knowledge International) to define openness in relation to data and content.[1] It specifies what licences for such material may and may not stipulate, in order to be considered open licences.[2] The definition itself was derived from the Open Source Definition for software.[2]OKI summarise the document as:[1].mw-parser-output .templatequote{overflow:hidden;margin:1em 0;padding:0 40px}.mw-parser-output .templatequote .templatequotecite{line-height:1.5em;text-align:left;padding-left:1.6em;margin-top:0}Open means anyone can freely access, use, modify, and share for any purpose (subject, at most, to requirements that preserve provenance and openness).The latest form of the document, published in November 2015, is version 2.1.[2] The use of language in the document is conformant with RFC 2119.[2]The document is available under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License,[1] which itself meets the Open Definition.
Contents1</text><lastUpdated>2019-09-02 17:46:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_Archives_and_Records_Administration</url><title>National Archives and Records Administration</title><text>independent agency of the United States government which preserves and provides access to federal records"NARA" redirects here. For the defunct immigration agency of Pakistan, see National Alien Registration Authority. For other uses, see Nara (disambiguation).

National Archives and Records AdministrationNARASealNational Archives logo, a stone eagle inspired by the architecture of the National Archives Building in Washington, D.C.[1]Agency overviewFormedJune 19, 1934; 85 years ago (1934-06-19)(Independent Agency April 1, 1985)[2]Preceding agencyNational Archives and Records Service (GSA)TypeIndependentJurisdictionU.S. Federal GovernmentHeadquartersNational Archives Building700 Pennsylvania Avenue NW, Washington, D.C., U.S.Employees3,112 (2014)[3]Annual budget$391 million (FY 2012)[4]Agency executivesDavid Ferriero, Archivist[5]Debra Steidel Wall, Deputy Archivist[6]Child agency</text><lastUpdated>2020-04-22 11:07:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenCores</url><title>OpenCores</title><text>open-source hardware community  OpenCores is a community developing digitalopen-source hardware through electronic design automation, with a similar ethos as the free software movement. OpenCores hopes to eliminate redundant design work and slash development costs. A number of companies have been reported as adopting OpenCores IP in chips,[1][2] or as adjuncts to EDA tools.[3][4] OpenCores is also cited from time to time in the electronics press as an example of open source in the electronics hardware community.[5]OpenCores has always been a commercially owned organization. In 2015, the core active users of OpenCores established the independent Free and Open Source Silicon Foundation (FOSSi Foundation), and registered the libreCores.org[6] website as the basis for all future development, independent of commercial control.
Contents1History2Licensing3The OpenCores library4OpenRISC ASIC5</text><lastUpdated>2020-04-25 05:13:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Winger</url><title>Richard Winger</title><text>Richard Lee Winger (born August 27, 1943) is an American political activist and analyst. He is the publisher and editor of Ballot Access News. He sits on the editorial board of the Election Law Journal. Winger publishes analysis, statistics and legal information and supports more equitable laws allowing access to the ballot for minor parties.[1][2][3][4][5]Winger is widely regarded as an expert on ballot access and election law.[6][7][8][9]
Though not a lawyer, he testifies in court cases and legislative hearings and is a source for media and political organizers.[10][11][12][13] He has been published in The Wall Street Journal, Journal of Election Law, the Fordham Urban Law Review, American Review of Politics, California Journal and other publications.[14] He has appeared as a commentator on ballot access on NBC, ABC, CNN, and NPR</text><lastUpdated>2020-03-06 08:19:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_Source_Ecology</url><title>Open Source Ecology</title><text>Open Source EcologyAbbreviationOSEFormation2003; 17 years ago (2003)HeadquartersFactor e FarmLocationMaysville, Missouri, USA.[1][2]Region served WorldwideEDMarcin JakubowskiBudget  $4,000 monthlyWebsiteOpensourceecology.orgPlay media  Open Source Ecology: Practical post scarcity  The 50 machines that compose the Global Village Construction SetOpen Source Ecology (OSE) is a network of farmers, engineers, architects and supporters, whose main goal is the eventual manufacturing of the Global Village Construction Set (GVCS). As described by Open Source Ecology "the GVCS is an open technological platform that allows for the easy fabrication of the 50 types of industrial machines that it takes to build a small civilization with modern comforts".[3] Groups in Oberlin, Ohio, Pennsylvania, New York and </text><lastUpdated>2020-04-29 19:26:00</lastUpdated></item>
<item><url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_music_model</url><title>Open music model</title><text>